

SKILLS

Frontend development
Micro-frontends
Architecture
Staring projects from scratch
Testing
Infrastructure
Investigation
Backend development

Mentoring Leadership Team organizing Tasks assignment

CONTACT

P: +48 662 921 496 P: +375 29 212 0592

E: alexsharabayko@gmail.com W: alexsharabayko.github.io

City: Warsaw

SOCIAL

fb: @alexsharabayko inst: @alexsharabayko github: @alexsharabayko

ALEX SHARABAYKO

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

ABOUT

Hi there! My name is Alexander I have been working as a frontend developer since 2013 and I'm still passionate about my job. Usually I participate in big-size long-term projects but also I have experience with small ones. Familiar with mentoring and team leadership.

I'm able to take care of establishing a project or a set of projects, its architecture and moving it in needed direction. I also don't mind working on more usual tasks like bug fixing, creating markups, etc.

I also have enough personal and communication skills to understand what and how we need to implement to achieve best user experience and meet business goals.

I have experience in backend as well: I've implemented middle-size servers using Laravel, Strapi. It would be nice to work with BE too.

Except work I like various types of activities like cooking, reading, cycling or boxing. Not a big extreme guy but not a home guy.

You are also can look at my web resume: https://alexsharabayko.github.io/

I'm open for both remote and in-office positions. Currently in Warsaw.

Nice to meet you!

TECHNICAL SKILLS

JAVASCRIPT / TYPESCRIPT

Level: advanced

• Vanilla JS, Angular, Rx JS, React JS, Redux, Web Components

HTML/CSS

Level: advanced

• HTML5, CSS3, Sass/Scss, Styled Components

BUNDLERS / INFRASTRUCTURE

Level: intermediate

• Webpack, Jenkins, Docker, AWS, CI/CD, Unit testing, Storybook

BACKAND LANGUAGES

Level: intermediate

• Node js (Express, Strapi), PHP (Laravel), Python

MOBILE DEVELOPMENT

Level: intermediate

• React Native, Ionic, adaptive/responsive markups



SKILLS

Frontend development
Micro-frontends
Architecture
Staring projects from scratch
Testing
Infrastructure
Investigation
Backend development

Mentoring Leadership Team organizing Tasks assignment

CONTACT

P: +48 662 921 496 P: +375 29 212 0592

E: alexsharabayko@gmail.com W: alexsharabayko.github.io

City: Warsaw

SOCIAL

fb: @alexsharabayko inst: @alexsharabayko github: @alexsharabayko

ALEX SHARABAYKO

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

WORK EXPERIENCE

LEAD FRONTEND DEVELOPER

IDT Corporation | May 2019 - Current

Tech stack: Angular, React, Web Components, Jenkins, Docker, Sip JS, HTML/SCSS, WebRTC, Redux, Rx JS. Webpack, Node JS

Working as a frontend tech lead and a scrum master on net2phone - a VOIP solution for small/medium size companies.

- Implementation of "micro-frontend" architecture in the product
- Developed common UI library of components which can work with any framework
- Started projects from scratch
- Feature implementations
- Bug fixing
- Team mentoring and leadership
- Scrum mastering
- Working on non-standard tech task like SIP issues, WebRTC or addon for Google Calendar
- Requirements clarification and documentation

FRONTEND / BACKEND DEVELOPER, CO-FOUNDER

Oh What App | Mar 2020 - Mar 2021

Tech stack: React Native, Strapi, Node JS, Postgres, Firebase

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.ohsmmmobile My friends and I were trying to create our own sophisticated app for SMM in Instagram. Minimal goal for me - learning a backend development.

- Participated in frontend development on React Native
- Created the server for this app using Strapi CMS
- Features / UX discussions

FRONTEND / BACKEND DEVELOPER, CO-FOUNDER

Healthgoing | Mar 2020 - Sep 2021

Tech stack: Angular, RxJS, HTML/Tailwind, Laravel, Stripe, WebRTC, Web sockets, Node JS

https://healthgoing.com/

My friends and I are trying to create solution to connect nutritionists with their customers.

- Started and participated in frontend development on Angular
- Created the server for this app using Laravel framework for PHP
- Features / UX discussions

SENIOR FRONTEND DEVELOPER

Exp Capital | Aug 2018 - May 2019

Tech stack: Angular, Ionic

Participated in development of https://capital.com/ and https://currency.com/ as a senior frontend dev.

- Participated in frontend development with Angular and Ionic
- Bug fixing



SKILLS

Frontend development
Micro-frontends
Architecture
Staring projects from scratch
Testing
Infrastructure
Investigation
Backend development

Mentoring Leadership Team organizing Tasks assignment

CONTACT

P: +48 662 921 496 P: +375 29 212 0592 E: alexsharabayko@gmail.com W: alexsharabayko.github.io City: Warsaw

SOCIAL

fb: @alexsharabayko inst: @alexsharabayko github: @alexsharabayko

ALEX SHARABAYKO

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

WORK EXPERIENCE

MIDDLE / SENIOR FRONTEND DEVELOPER

Viaden Media / Skywind | Sept 2014 - Jul 2018

Tech stack: Angular, React JS,HTML/CSS/SASS, Angular, Node JS, Electron, Backbone JS, jQuery,

Started as a middle frontend developer. At first helped my team to develop https://www.galabingo.com/ and https://www.galacasino.com/ - fixed bugs, implementing new features on Backbone.

Then participated in development of internal Backoffice using angular and started Electron app from scratch for our customers.

- Participated in frontend development using Backbone, Angular, React
- Bug fixing
- Started Electron / Angular desktop app from scratch
- Feature implementations
- Bug fixing
- Team mentoring

JUNIOR FRONTEND DEVELOPER

HiQo Solutions | Jul 2013 - Aug 2014 Tech stack: JS, HTML/CSS, jQuery, Backbone

Starting point of my career. Was member of internship program then worked as junior engineer: fixed bugs, implemented small features for different projects, for example https://www.hiqo-solutions.com

- Participated in frontend development on vanilla JS, jQuery
- Bugs fixing
- Small features implementations

EDUCATION

BACHELOR DEGREE - MATH FACULTY
Belarusian State University | 2010 - 2015

THE COMPLETE NODE.JS DEVELOPER COURSE PYTHON AND DJANGO FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER BOOTCAMP BUILD A BACKEND REST API WITH PYTHON & DJANGO

Udemy